KOLDO OTEO ORELLANA

Phone: +34 611 424 080 / koldo.oteo@gmail.com / https://linkedin.com/in/sitereliabilityengineering/en / https://github.com/SiteReliabilityEngineering / http://sitereliabilityengineer.io

Address: GENERAL PARDINAS 64, MADRID (MADRID) SPAIN / Nationality: Spanish (EU Wok permit)

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER PROFILE

Senior system administrator with extensive (+15years) experience with Redhat / Linux/ Unix O.S, middleware, networking, scripting, performance and tuning. Ability to develop and maintain close working relationships with my team. Autodidact with great ability on resolution of complicated issues. Self-motivated team player who demonstrates **initiative** and **flexibility**. Trying to make a step into **devops** world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Unix/Linux: Redhat Enterprise Server, CentOS, Suse, Debian, Ubuntu, Solaris, Tru64, OpenBSD, FreeBSD, etc...

Programming languages: Python, shell scripting (bash), previously with ruby.

Configuration management: Starting with ansible. Implementing into dev and pre-production environments.

Source control: Some git personal experience.

Others: SSL Certificates, tcpdump/Wireshark, LVM, bind, nagios, KVM, etc...

Webservers: Apache, nginx, etc...

Middleware: WebLogic, Oracle Application Server, Jboss, Tomcat.

Performance-tuning: Big experience on middleware tuning, eclipse mat, samurai, visualvm, jconsole.

Databases: Oracle database and mysql, not as a DBA.

Firewalls: iptables, firewalld, fw1, openbsd pf.

LDAP: Oracle internet directory, OpenIdap, Sun One, IBM secureway.

Languages: English, Portuguese, Spanish (native)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior system/middleware administrator at Health Ministry of Madrid with Fujitsu.

Nov 2008 - Present

Working on a high end environment at the health ministry of Madrid State, managing all the health canter's and hospitals of the state, on a proactive team providing the very highest level of technical support and customer service. Administration of 3 data centre's with +400 server's. With on call 24 * 7.

Daily tasks:

- Installing and configuring servers with redhat enterprise server and LVM configuration.
- Creation of automation tools with Python, bash (alerts, mails, statistics, maintenance) and previously (ruby).
- Installation of 3 data centres from 0.
- Operating system tuning.
- NFS / SAMBA resources configuration.
- Installing and configuration of WebLogic 11G/12c server's, oas, Jboss, apache, tomcat, etc...
- Creation of SSL Certificates / containers and all related tasks.

- Java middleware server's/http server's performance and tuning and heap dump analysis.
- Day by day investigation on strange issues in very critical applications.
- Middleware server / system / application upgrades.
- KVM virtual machines administration and now migrating to vmware.
- Configuration of smtp (sendmail, postfix) and dns (bind).
- Implementing Ansible in development and pre-production environments.
- Trained new employees.

Senior System administrator at Siemens Healthcare with abama tech.

Jul 2005 - Nov 2008

Working for Siemens healthcare group, giving third level support on hospitals all over Spain. With very critical systems. With on call 24 * 7.

Daily tasks:

- Installation and maintenance of Solaris, redhat and windows server's.
- Installation of JRUN, tomcat, oracle application servers.
- Oracle internet directory, ibm secureway, sun one, openIdap configuration.
- Oracle 9i administration.
- OID AD authentication delegation.
- Middleware and http server's performance and tuning.
- Radwareload balancer configuration.
- Configuration of pf/ipf firewalls on FreeBSD/OpenBSD.
- Responsible of the migration from windows to Linux servers.
- Responsible of the migration of IBM secureway to Oracle internet directory or to Sun ONE.
- Prime cluster (Fujitsu cluster) on Solaris servers.

Level II System administrator at Terra Networks.

Feb 2003 - Jun 2004

Level II administration of terra networks/Telefonica .net data centre's at Pozuelo (Madrid). With on call 24 * 7.

Daily tasks:

- Our mission is to resolve 80% of the issues.
- Administration of windows with IIS.
- Administration of Linux with JRun.
- ColdFusion administration.
- LDAP Administration.

Operator / Sysadmin at IP SISTEMAS

Oct 2000 - Nov 2002

Working at few projects: Eresmas data center, cpd on the box.

Daily tasks:

- System operator at eresmas data center.
- Cisco catalyst 6900 configuration.
- Windows, redhat, suse, solaris, aix, irix installation and configuration.
- Apache configuration.
- iPlanet smtp configuration.

- Administration of Sun netras.
- Servers security supervision.

EDUCATION

Master -Tru64 Unix (COMPAQ) and Oracle - (Procesos integrales de formación.)

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

June 2017 Doing python bootcamp course at Udemy.

June 2017 Finished Udemy course: Python Bible.

16 Dec 2016 Passed: Red hat Certified system administrator "RHCSA" (RHEL7) certification id 160-265-187

Aug 2016 Linux Academy Red Hat Certified Systems Administrator Prep Course.

Apr 2016 Weblogic system administration, diagnostics and troubleshooting course.

Feb 2012 Pentesting web applications workshop with Chema Alonso (madridonrails).

Mar 2011 Weblogic Workshop.

Jun 2010 ITIL Foundations V3.

2007 Certification on Fujitsu Primepower Servers

2000 ASE certification on Tru64 Unix, ASE storageworks certification, ASE on web environment, Oracle Database courses: plsql, performance & tuning, etc...

1999 NT/Novell/Unix networks (Nuevas tecnologías Madrid)

ADITIONAL INFORMATION / INTERESTS

- Daily self-training related to Linux / scripting / networking, because I'm a passionate of these areas.
- I enjoy travelling as I have a keen interest in other cultures and ways of life. I feel I learnt the importance of independence and understanding the ways of others.
- I love all kind of sports, but I prefer the ones that feel in contact with the nature, like snorkelling, trekking, etc...
- Cooking international dishes is another hobby, to keep in contact with other cultures.